ABDUL BASIT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT DETAILS

Phone no: +92 316-8806813 Email: basitdevv@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/BasitDev

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdul-basit-549b3022a/

PROFILE SUMMARY

I'm an experienced MERN developer with nearly 2 years of experience. I'm good with databases, JavaScript, and TypeScript. I also know how to use Git and have worked with cloud platforms like AWS. I love solving tough problems with smart solutions. I'm great at making web apps that can handle lots of users and are easy to maintain. I'm a team player but can also work on my own, and I always make sure to deliver top-notch work on time. I'm open to new opportunities and excited to work with others to make cool digital stuff

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- React.js
- Next.js
- Typescript
- Tailwind
- Digital Ocean
- Git

- Node.js
- Express.js
- Nest.js
- AWS (Amazon Web Services)
- MySQL
- MongoDB

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

STATUS 200 PRIVATE LTD. DEC 2022 – PRESENT SE (FULL STACK DEVELOPER)

- Brought many web applications to life using React.js.
- Created scalable and robust backend architectures using Express, Nest.js integrated with MongoDB databases.
- Integrated multiple third-party APIs such as SendGrid, Equifax, Twilio, Maps, TOVO
 Data etc.
- Deployed numerous applications on servers like AWS, Digital Ocean, and Ionos.
- Set up a streamlined flow for deployment using CI/CD with GitHub Actions.
- Conducted sessions with clients and technical discussions with developers.
- Trained and mentored junior developers and interns on best practices and development techniques.

FIVED. AUG 2022 - DEC 2022

JR. FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Utilized React, Next.js, Angular to build scalable web applications.
- Implemented Express.js, and Mongo DB to manage server-side operations.
- Integrated third-party APIs to enhance the functionality and features of web applications.
- Designed and developed RESTful APIs
- Assisting team lead on multiple projects
- Collaborated with team members to deliver projects within tight deadlines.

FIVED. **OCT 2021 – MARCH 2021**

WEB DEVELOPER TRAINEE

- Built web applications using React.js, Express.js, and MongoDB.
- Developed proficiency in modern web development technologies and expanded skills in database management.
- End-to-end Mobile Responsive UI Designing
- Understanding Requirements
- Learning about new libraries and frameworks
- Write custom code for existing websites. Maintaining Websites

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

BACHELORS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE 2018 - 2022

COMSAT UNIVERSITY ISLAMABAD, ABBOTTABAD CAMPUS

PRE-ENGINEERING 2016 - 2018

NATIONAL COLLEGE OF SCIENCES

PROJECT DEVELOPED

VOUCHPAD

BACKEND: NEST - DATABASE: MONGODB - WEB INTERFACE: ANGULAR - DEPLOYMENT: AWS

A B2C marketplace for Students to Apply for Student loans. Constitutes a system that involves custom CRM involving multi-user types such as super admin, staff, and banker/partner user. It's a FinTech application that has a FAIR Rating algorithm, Equifax for Credit scores, Backed with Push notifications, email notifications, and certain flags assigned to a particular loan application.

Link: https://www.vouchpad.com

AL-KHALIJIAH

BACKEND: NODE - DATABASE: MONGODB - WEB INTERFACE: REACT - DEPLOYMENT: DIGITAL OCEAN

Designed and deployed Al Khalijiah's IT services website using MERN stack and Deployed on Digital Ocean. Developed pixel-perfect frontend, and a robust and scalable backend, admin panel for efficient content and data management. Showcased strong technical skills and met client requirements.

Link: https://khalijiah.com/

DAVID ELLIS PORTFOLIO

BACKEND: NODE - DATABASE: MONGODB - WEB INTERFACE: REACT - DEPLOYMENT: AWS

This product consists of two desktop applications built on PyQt5, designed specifically for car dealership showrooms. These applications allow dealerships to track and monitor the performance of their salespeople in real time on a daily basis. Additionally, there is a mobile application available for upper-level staff to use for monitoring purposes.

Link: https://www.davidellis.co.uk/

EMPYREAL EXCHANGE

BACKEND: NODE - DATABASE: MONGODB - WEB INTERFACE: REACT - DEPLOYMENT: VERCEL

I independently developed a captivating 3D animated landing page for a metaverse company using React.js and the Three.js library. To enhance the visual appeal, I leveraged additional resources such as Framer Motion. My goal was to exceed client expectations by delivering a pixel-perfect, responsive website that seamlessly adapts to all screen sizes.

Link: https://empyreal-exchange.vercel.app/

ENRAPTURE – REALITY BROKEN

BACKEND: NODE - DATABASE: MONGODB - WEB INTERFACE: REACT - DEPLOYMENT: AWS

I played a vital role in creating 'Enrapture,' a dynamic MERN website with Three.js and GSAP. It offers innovative 3D and Metaverse AR/VR services. My work involved building the admin panel, front-end 3D animations, and integrating APIs. We also added email notifications, newsletter sign-ups, blogs, and analytics for user engagement.

Link: https://enrapture.world/
Link: https://blog.enrapture.world/

BREAKCOMP – SPORT CARDS

BACKEND: NODE - DATABASE: MONGODB - WEB INTERFACE: REACT - DEPLOYMENT: AWS

Break Comp is a card price comparison website that caters to collectors and enthusiasts of sports cards, providing them with a convenient platform to compare prices across various vendors and sellers.

Link: https://breakcomp.com/